

Hamburg, Germany

🛘 (+49) 172 7748405 | 🗷 prado.renann@gmail.com | 🏕 https://renann.me | 🖸 renannprado | 🖹 renann | 🛅 renannprado

Summary

Software Architect with 8+ years of experience in software architecture, development, production support and database design. I'm always striving to keep a good balance between delivery time and quality while also motivated to lead and work with multiple teams encouraging innovation, creativity, simplicity and productivity. I also have greater interest in: continuous integration and continuous delivery automation; designing simple, scalable and distributed applications; cloud, container orchestration and (micro)services.

Skills

TECHNICAL

Java, Golang, Spring Boot, HTTP and testing

Proficient Kotlin, gRPC, SQL, Redis, Kubernetes, Docker, websockets, JWT, Jenkins, Google Cloud Platform

Familiar Shellscript, nginx, PHP, Javascript, Typescript, Node.js

Getting Started Rust, VueJS, Flutter, GraalVM, Micronaut, Apache Kafka

SPEAKING LANGUAGES

Portuguese - Native | English - Fluent | Spanish - good understanding | German - A1.1

Work Experience _____

Engel & Völkers Technology GmbH

Hamburg, Germany

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Jun. 2019 - present

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Abr. 2018 - Jun. 2019

- · Design, discuss and plan architecture changes, keep track of technical debts, sprint planning, leading, mentoring, code reviewing, software development and CI/CD automation
- Leading a software development team of two other developers
- · Technical advising, leading effort, discussions of product refactoring and rewriting, leading multiple products to have lower maintenance and complexity

Portal Export: Helped to refactor part of the product architecture, leading to: reduction of the number of microservices from expected 87 to 11, easier maintenance and less costs

Master Data: Rearchitected the whole product, reducing the number of microservices from 6 to 1, better overall architecture and lower maintenance costs

Globe: Technical advice/guidance for external offshore team when needed

- · Research on Keycloak to have it as our company SSO solution
- · Planning migration from legacy applications to newly developed applications
- Integration of our system with SaaS such as Freshdesk, SAP ByDesign and Salesforce
- · Automated gRPC library generation targeting multiple languages using Jenkins and Docker
- Stack: Git, Golang, Java/Kotlin, Sprint Boot, Dart, Flutter, gRPC, REST, Swagger, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, AsciiDoc, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform, GCP PubSub, GCP Bucket, Firestore, Cloud Functions and Datadog

Avenue Code São Paulo, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2018

Worked as a third party developer for eBay

San Jose, USA Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2018

Mar. 2016 - Sep. 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR FROM AVENUE CODE)

- · Machine learning model deployment automation: a set of microservices to manage training, storage and deployment of machine learning models
- Travelled to USA for application development support for 5 months
- Stack: Git, Java, Sprint Boot, Docker, Kubernetes and in-house proprietary tools

UOL (Universo Online) São Paulo, Brazil

• Architected together with the team, a product from scratch for the first time

- Implemented websocket to be used for in-browser notifications
- CI automation and application packaging (.rpm files) with Jenkins
- Stack: Git, SVN, Jetty, Oracle Database, MySQL, Redis, memcached, websockets, MongoDB, nginx, Java, Spring Boot, Maven, Node.js, PHP, Apache HTTPD, Riak, Golang, Cucumber, Mockito, Kubernetes, Docker, Swagger, Prometheus and Grafana

RENANN PRADO · RÉSUMÉ MARCH 29, 2020

Agile Solutions São Paulo, Brazil

TECHNICAL LEAD

May. 2015 - Mar. 2016

Consultant Software Developer

Oct. 2013 - Apr. 2015

· Worked as a third party developer for Iron Mountain and SAP

- Also worked on a company owned ERP product written in Node.js
- Stack: Git, Node.js and SAP HANA database

SAP Palo Alto, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR FROM AGILE SOLUTIONS)

thad an a few proof of concept projects of SAP's clients

- Worked on a few proof of concept projects of SAP's clients
- Travelled to USA for application development support for 5 months
- for Cisco:

Developed backend and frontend application for electronic components management/quotation

Stack: Git, AngularJS, D3.js, CSS3, HTML5, SASS, Grunt, Bower, JBoss (JEE), Java, Hibernate and REST

for PKFitness:

Developed a websocket based application for real time transmission of data points of marathonists watches to the cloud

Developed load tests for the websocket application Helped to develop the frontend application as well

Stack: Git, Tomcat, Java, Node.js, D3.js, websocket, AngularJS and Bootstrap

SAP Palo Alto, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR FROM AGILE SOLUTIONS)

May. 2014 - Jun. 2015

Jul. 2015 - Sep. 2015

- Worked on single product called SAP Consumer Insight 365
- Lead a small team of three developers for some time
- · Dealt responsibly with very sensitive mobile providers' data
- Developed data structure library based on Java's off-heap memory using the Unsafe API aiming for high speed a low memory consumption
- Developed ETL processes to aggregate mobile provider's data and load into SAP HANA database
- Travelled to USA for application development support for 5 months
- Stack: Git, Maven, Java, and other proprietary tools

Iron Mountain Boston, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACTOR FROM AGILE SOLUTIONS)

Oct. 2013 - May. 2014

- · Software development, testing and application deployment using the following
- Travelled to USA for application development support for 1 month
- Stack: Talend MDM, JBoss EAP 5.2, JBoss AS 7.1.1, Tomcat, MySQL and Oracle DBs, WebServices, Java Enterprise Edition, JSF, Primefaces, SOAP UI, Hibernate, Maven, Unix Environments

Amdocs São Carlos, Brazil

JUNIOR SYSTEMS ANALYST

Abr. 2012 - Oct. 2013

- Analyse, unit test, develop, test support and production environments of CRM applications for telecommunications companies, specifically in Ordering lifecycle module
- · Received product customization training in São Paulo for a month and I continued the training in Israel for more 2 months
- Participated in UAT (User Acceptance Tests) on site support for NET Brazil project in São Paulo
- Travelled to Colombia for 2 months to support UAT and application integration with external systems
- Stack: Java, Spring, JNLP, Oracle, Eclipse, HP Quality Center, custom version control system and other in-house frameworks for both desktop and backend development

Synchron Informática São Carlos, Brazil

JUNIOR PROGRAMMER

Mar. 2012 - Abr. 2012

- ERP application development and support
- · Learned a few new technologies and gave production support for the first time
- Stack: Team Foundation Server, VB.net, Asp.net, jQuery, Ajax, C, Windows Forms and SQL Server database

Projects

skillstream.dev

CREATOR

- A website that let render a timeline of your skills during your lifetime as a developer
- Stack: Golang, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Google Cloud, GCP Cloud Run and GCP Bucket

Education

Instituto Federal de São Paulo (IFSP)

São Carlos, Brazil

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN ANALYSIS AND SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

Feb. 2009 - Dez. 2011